<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>IndianFaith</title>
        <description>IndianFaith - </description>
        <link></link>
        <link></link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-08-31T21:06:37+05:30</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-08-31T21:06:37+05:30</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Central Illinois Mosque & Islamic Center</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Illinois Mosque and Islamic Center, also known as CIMIC, is a religious, not-for-profit organization affiliated with the Islamic Society of North America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of CIMIC is to advance the cause of Islam and serve Muslims in East Central Illinois. CIMIC aims to provide coordination of local Muslim affairs, establish educational opportunities for local Muslims of all ages, foster a positive understanding of Islam in American society, and promote a spirit of brotherhood and equality and a commitment to justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events organized by mosque volunteers serve the Muslim community of Central Illinois and the community of Champaign-Urbana at large. The mosque seeks to promote a nurturing educational environment, a family-friendly social environment, interfaith events with the community at large, and social activism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our structure includes a library, classrooms and a multi-purpose area. This space is used for Weekend Islamic School for children, Arabic school for people of all ages, and English classes for immigrants. The space is also used for tae-kwon-do classes twice a week as well as ping-pong tournaments and youth group activities. The mosque provides a place for small weddings, Eid celebrations and daily iftar meals in Ramadan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/muslim/central-illinois-mosque-islamic-center/</link>
                <guid>/muslim/central-illinois-mosque-islamic-center</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-31T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>ISKCON Chicago</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;History&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hare Krishna movement has its roots 5000 years ago in the teachings of Lord Krishna, the supreme personality of Godhead.  The movement was introduced to the western world by His Divine Grace A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada in 1965 and it rapidly spread all over the world in a matter of 12 years and we have quadrupled in size since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hare Krishna movement includes mantra meditation (japa), music (kirtan), food (prasadam), philosophy and festivals. It is a part of our daily lives!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bhagavad Gita focuses on the spiritual nourishment of the soul thereby guaranteeing inner happiness and contentment for the sincere practitioner. The simple process is to connect our daily lives with the supreme spiritual personality, Lord Krishna. So the food we eat, the music we hear, the object of our meditation and the basis of our relationships with one another are all centered around the same focal point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic philosophy begins with the understanding that we are not this body, rather we are the conscious spiritual beings residing in these varieties of material bodies resembling humans, aquatics, plants, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The humble sages, by virtue of true knowledge, see with equal vision a learned and gentle brahmana, a cow, an elephant, a dog and a dog-eater….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bhagavad Gita&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover the spiritual beings residing in all these varieties of life-forms are parts and parcels of the supreme personality of Godhead, Lord Krishna. So on the spiritual platform we are all equal and we experience real happiness when connected to our source. This is Yoga which means “to connect” in Sanskrit. Connection of the soul with the supreme through loving devotional service is called Bhakti Yoga. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real happiness can be derived only from a spiritual source, just like a fish can derive happiness only in water, not outside. We are spirit souls and our happiness comes from loving relationships with other spiritual beings, what to speak of the joy that is experienced when we are connected to the supreme spiritual being, Krishna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even our smart devices are so attractive not because of the glass, metal or plastic, but because these objects connect us to another persons.  Thus to love and be loved is real spiritual nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practical application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you walk into the temple especially during Krishna Fest (every Sunday), you will experience the true unity in diversity in our ISKCON Chicago family where 40+ nationalities are represented. We serve together, dance together, learn together and build strong friendships forgetting our superficial differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISKCON Chicago offer many regular spiritual educational programs throughout Chicagoland helping people understand how to become happy and how to live a lifestyle in harmony with the laws of nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 100,000 plates of Karma Free food is served every year. It is Karma Free because it is pure vegetarian food, cooked with love and offered to Krishna with gratitude, acknowledging Him as its source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mantra meditation or Japa is the basis of all our activities. We chant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hare Krishna Hare Krishna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krishna Krishna Hare Hare&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hare Rama Hare Rama&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rama Rama Hare Hare&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer regular Meditation Workshops and you can also come to one of our daily meditation sessions every morning from 5:15 am to 7 am at the temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have festivals every week and major festivals practically every month of the year. These festivals are free and surcharged with inspiration to boost are spiritual lives!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process of Krishna Consciousness is simply joyful and natural. Thus it very quickly expanding all over the world, to every town and village giving genuine happiness to millions people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite you to experience this happiness. You can start by coming to one of our Krishna Fests at the temple, or a college program near or study group near you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/hindu/Sri-Sri-Kishore-Kishori-Temple/</link>
                <guid>/hindu/Sri-Sri-Kishore-Kishori-Temple</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-27T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Sri Venkateswara Temple - Balaji</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Thousands of devotees from the mid western states, especially from Chicago land used to travel to Pittsburgh to have darshan of Sri Venkateswara swami. While the experience was spiritually rewarding, the time and effort required to make the trip was making it difficult for many to have his darshan as often as their hearts desired. Many felt a void in their spiritual lives and their discontent was wide spread. The state of affairs continued until 1985. As a result of philanthropy of nine families who donated 20 acres of land with a farm house in Aurora (a far west suburb of Chicago), as a site for the proposed Balaji temple, a beginning was made in the realization of a dream of many. Since Sri Venkateswara swami (Balaji) temple is an institution that has to serve innumerable generations to come, plans were drawn on a magnificent scale related to the means available and the needs of the moment. No pains were spared in making its designs meet the agamic space requirements when at the same time ensuring that it also meets the local building codes, structural safety standards and the needs of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Padmasri M.Muthiah Sthapathy, a noted expert on temple construction in India collaborated with Sri Subhash Nadkarni, a reputed architect of Chicago and a devotee of Balaji, and together they designed the temple. This design is an excellent blend of ancient Shilpa shastra and modern architectural technology. This design also served as a model for other temples that were built later in the United States. A unique feature of the temple is provision for circumambulation (pradakshina) inside the temple not only around the presiding deity, but around all the major shrines inside the temple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/hindu/Balaji-Temple/</link>
                <guid>/hindu/Balaji-Temple</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-25T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Sikh Religious Society of Chicago</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sikh Resource Society is located in the Midwest and offers services such as free tours for public/private schools, collages and universities as well as individual tours to those that would like to understand better their global Sikh neighbor. The Sikh Resource Society also has speakers who are willing to give a presentation on the Sikh faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tours are mainly held at the Gurdwara Sahib that is located at 1280 Winnetka Street, Palatine, IL; on a campus spread over fourteen acres of land at a prime location in Chicago’s metropolitan area. The Palatine Gurdwara is the oldest Gurdwara in the Midwest, started in 1972. In a seven day a week religious program, devotees visit the Gurdwara Sahib to make prayers, listen to the Sikh religious hymns (Kirtan), and discourses on spirituality.Tours are conducted at a nearby Gurdwara, including Palatine (Sikh Religious Society of Chicago), Wheaton (Illinois Sikh Community Center), Devon (Devon Gurdwara Sahib), and other Gurdwaras (Sikh place of worship) in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/sikh/Sikh-Religious-Society-of-Chicago/</link>
                <guid>/sikh/Sikh-Religious-Society-of-Chicago</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-24T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Chicago Mar Thoma Church</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Parish in itself is a history and desire of people to be with Lord the creator and protector….
In the early seventies around twenty families were assembling for heartfelt worship at their own apartments or houses. The late former Metropolitan, Most Rev. Dr. Alexander Mar Thoma (Alexander Mar Theophilus Episcopa that time) on his visit to Chicago in May 1973 encouraged the small group of Mar Thomites in the Chicago land to meet for regular worship which became Chicago Mar Thoma group. With the steady influx of Malayalee immigrants, the group registered in March 1977 in the state of Illinois as not-for-profit organization. The group received assignment of pastoral services for the first time in September 1977; the Mar Thoma Synod approved the group as a congregation in May 1978. As the congregation continued to grow spiritually and in membership, the congregation was elevated to Parish status in Aug 1981. A full time Vicar was assigned in 1983 for Chicago Mar Thoma Church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members strong desire to have their own place for worship instead of rented buildings resulted in the formation of a Church building committee in 1983 and in January 1985 the existing land at 240 Potter Road was purchased. Most Rev. Dr. Alexander Mar Thoma Metropolitan in July 14, 1985 laid the foundation stone for a new Church. In November 1986, Rt. Rev. Thomas Mar Timotheos dedicated the new Church as Chicago Mar Thoma Church. The Church acquired another acre of land in august 1988 for Parsonage building. In the history of Chicago Mar Thoma Church, it became a mother parish when Bethel Mar Thoma Church was dedicated in Frankfort, IL. In the year 1995 Parish received another recognition, service of an Assistant Vicar and the Parish purchased a new Parsonage building. The continued growth of the parish made Parish to buy another piece of land for a second Church in Lombard, IL. In the year 2004 as per the Kalpana of Metropolitan 110 families of Chicago Mar Thoma Church became members of St Thomas Mar Thoma Church which eventually built the current structure of St. Thomas Mar Thoma Church at Lombard, IL thus making Chicago Mar Thoma Church mother parish for the second time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Chicago Mar Thoma Church is the second largest Parish in North America and Europe diocese. Praise Lord for the ways and means he guided the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/christian/Chicago-Mar-Thoma-Church/</link>
                <guid>/christian/Chicago-Mar-Thoma-Church</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-24T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>The Hindu Temple of Greater Chicago</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hindu Temple of Greater Chicago in Lemont, IL has been in the forefront for over three decades in helping many seeking to actively continue of traditional Indian religious and cultural values in US. Today, the temple, in addition to two main temples, Sri Rama and Ganesh-Shiva-Durga temples, has a Vivekananda Statue and Vivekananda Spiritual Center that provides additional source to learn and experience spirituality. With the addition of this notable center and installation of Swamiji’s statue - the first one to be installed in a public place in United States of America, HTGC has become a prime center for religious, spritual and cultural activities for thousands of people in midwest states; Illinois, Wisconsin, Michigan, Indiana and Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complex provides a congenial atmosphere for worship and spiritual advancement. It also serves as a focal point cultural and educational activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hindu Temple of Greater Chicago is an Illinois general not-for-profit corporation, established in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of HTGC is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To establish and maintain Hindu Temples build and serviced in the traditional Hindu style.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To promote Hindu Dharma (religion and traditions) and culture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To promote inter-religious, social, and cultural understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To support humanitarian causes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>/hindu/the-hindu-temple-of-greater-chicago/</link>
                <guid>/hindu/the-hindu-temple-of-greater-chicago</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>The Buddhist Temple of Chicago</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Buddhist Temple of Chicago (BTC), now nearing its 71st anniversary, is one of the oldest Buddhist temples in Chicago. Our membership has historically been Japanese American, but the temple has diversified over the decades to include members of European, African, Asian, Latin, and Native American descent. We welcome those who identify as LGBTQ. We even have devout Christian members who believe that the teachings of the Buddha are compatible with their religion. Anyone wishing to learn about the Dharma is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTC is an administratively independent temple with a historical lineage rooted in the Japanese Pure Land tradition. All serving ministers have been ordained in the Higashi Honganji denomination of Jodo Shinshu and maintain strong ties to the head temple in Kyoto. Our temple offers meditation sessions on a regular basis, along with study classes covering a wide range of Buddhist teachings, such as the Sutta Nipata and the Lotus Sutra. We hold services nearly every Sunday morning at 11, in addition to hosting a wide variety of educational and cultural classes (see the Education link above). There are also several special Buddhist and Japanese culture events throughout the year. All services and classes are in English, except for the monthly Japanese service, which is held at 1 pm on the first Sunday of the month. At most services there are Spanish speakers available. In addition, we have amplification devices to assist the hearing-impaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temple was founded on October 8, 1944 by Rev. Gyomay M. Kubose, a pioneer in presenting Buddhism in everyday English and one of the first Jodo Shinshu ministers in the United States to conduct Zen meditation sessions. The original site was in Hyde Park on Chicago’s South Side. The temple is now located in the vibrant neighborhood of Uptown on the North Side. A new six-sided temple building modeled after the six-sided Rokkakudo Temple in Kyoto, Japan, was dedicated May 21, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/buddhist/the-buddhist-temple-of-chicago/</link>
                <guid>/buddhist/the-buddhist-temple-of-chicago</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Jain Society of Metropolitan Chicago</title>
                <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;jain-society-of-metropolitan-chicago-jsmc&quot;&gt;Jain Society of Metropolitan Chicago (JSMC):&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1970, the Jain Society of Metropolitan Chicago (JSMC) is a non-profit tax exempt organization registered in State of Illinois and operating under IRC Title 26 U.S.C. 501(c), Section 501(c)(3) status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSMC has a membership of about 1,500 families, the largest membership representation of the Jain Centers in North America. JSMC is a proud member of the Federation of Jain Associations In North America (JAINA) and has a distinctive honor of having built in 1992 the 1st significant Jain Temple of North America on 15.4 acre property it owns in Bartlett, Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jainism is a religion and a way of life for the Jains around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of JSMC is to provide a temple for religious services and a community center for social, cultural, educational and economic needs of the Jain community. Other objectives of JSMC are to increase the awareness of the principles of Jainism, achieve the unity of all Jains, provide a platform wherefrom to project the voice of Jain religion, promote the feeling of amity and brotherhood among Jains and to promote inter-faith understanding, establish communications between scholars of Jain philosophy and members of the Society, and celebrate Jain festivals and holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mission&quot;&gt;Mission:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To offer a trustworthy and structured ground for projecting a common voice of all Jains for promoting principles of Jain religion, providing Jain education to the community, and celebrating Jain social and cultural events in a manner that is compassionate, vibrant, &amp;amp; dynamic to all. In doing so, the organization shall execute its affairs ethically based on a sound infrastructure and responsible conduct, while creating a sustainable financial position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vision&quot;&gt;Vision:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To establish an inspiring Jain lifestyle that focuses on youth involvement, boasts the highest membership among Jain Centers outside of India, demonstrates having a positive impact on every stakeholder, grows financially to a stable and sustainable debt-free position, becomes a “can’t live without” for the community, and attracts visitors as a “must visit”place on Chicago’s list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>/jain/jain-society-of-metropolitan-chicago/</link>
                <guid>/jain/jain-society-of-metropolitan-chicago</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-22T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
